O N D U S O

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com | walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

PROFILE

I am a creative and proficient software developer specializing in web and mobile application development. A rich background in full life-cycle of software development process. I like to explore alternative solutions to problems and have an open mind about what will work best.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - Current

Senior Full stack Engineer

JOBDOH Limited

- Responsible for building high-quality, innovative and fully performing software that complies with coding standards and technical design.
- Re-Engineering of the Jobdoh Job Hailing Platform
- Champion of solid processes (TDD, code reviews, Kanban, continuous integration and
- Javascript backend senior developer with focus on web and mobile using: Node, Koa, Vue, Nativescript, GraphQL
- Championing Google Cloud Platform and Docker on Kubernetes;
- Designing NoSQL / ACID databases, as well as transactional and document databases;
- Advocating current best practices in frontend development;

2018 - 2019

Senior Software Consultant

Masterpiece Fusion Limited

Worked with upper management to define software requirements and take the lead on operational and technical projects

O N D U S O

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com | walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

- Acquired immense knowledge with configuration management tool Chef.
- Managing Amazon Web Services (AWS) infrastructure with automation and orchestration tools such as Chef
- Proficient in AWS services like VPC, EC2, S3, ELB, AutoScalingGroups(ASG), EBS, RDS, IAM, CloudFormation, Route 53, CloudWatch, CloudFront, CloudTrail.
- Involved in writing Java API for Amazon Lambda to manage some of the AWS services.
- Re-Engineering of the Online BidBond Generation Solution for NIC Bank
- Development of Informer a 360 degrees KYC System for NIC Bank
- Development of an E-wallet for NIC Bank
- Kenya Company Registrar Integrations
- Tingle Telcos Integrations

2016-2018

Senior Software Engineer

Smart Banking Solutions Africa

- Written cloud formation templates in json to create custom VPC, subnets, NAT to ensure successful deployment of web applications.
- Written Templates for AWS infrastructure as a code using Terraform to build staging and production environmentsRe-Engineerng of the ATM real time monitoring Portal for Diamond Trust Bank - Lead Developer
- Blockchain Integration to a Bill Payment Solution Lead Developer
- Development of an E-wallet Solution
- Merchant Payment and Sales Solution
- Integration to DTB Core Banking System ISO Communication for Virtual Card Generation. -Lead Developer

O N D U S O

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com | walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

- Used security groups, network ACL's, internet gateways and route tables to ensure a secure zone for organization in AWS public cloud.
- Used AWS Beanstalk for deploying and scaling web applications and services. Created and configured elastic load balancers and auto scaling groups to distribute the traffic and to have a cost efficient, fault tolerant and highly available environment.
- Possess good knowledge in creating and launching EC2 instances using AMI's of Linux, Ubuntu, RHEL, and Windows and wrote shell scripts to bootstrap instance

2013 - 2015

Software Engineer

Equity Bank Group

- Digitalisation of Bank Account opening process Developer
- Development of Camp[us Integrated Campus Card
- Equity Bank Group Eazzy mobile loan scale up to Kenya, Rwanda, Uganda and Tanzania Software
- Equity Bank digital products Eazzypay and Eazzy pay online software engineer
- Group data management software Engineer
- Equity Bank New Agency banking Solution -Software engineer
- Oracle Application Gateway (OAG) policies developer
 - o Oracle Service bus services (OSB) Developer
 - Continuous Integration (CI) and release management Developer

O N D U S O

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com

| walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

2011 - 2013

Positions

Co-operate and Retail Cashier

Account Opening Officer

Custodial Officer

M-pesa/Western Union Money

Line Officer

ABC Officer

Equity Bank Group

- Experienced following Banking Systems
- Cheque Truncation Systems
- Bank Transaction Processing and Maintenance Systems
- Mobile banking Systems
- Money Transfer systems ie: western Union, moneyline

EDUCATION

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of science

(Telecommunication and IT)

University

Key Area of Specialization

- Network administration
- Software Development

2006-2010

Kenya Certificate of Secondary

Education (KCSE)

Secondary

Schooled at Migori Boys High School

Attained Grade: A, AGP: 82

ONDUSO

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com

| walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

TOOLS

Operating systems:

linux, windows 95-8, MacOs

Programing Languages:

NODE JS, PHP, JAVA

Web development :

HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks:

Spring Boot, Play, Laravel, Express,

codeignitor

Design:

Adobe photoshop (GIMP)

APIs:

SOAP-based APIs, Restful APIs, ISO8583

APIs,

Sockets Communication APIs

Databases:

Mysql, Oracle, MongoDB

Technologies:

Blockchain and Machine Learning

SKILLS

- Extensive experience in software development, scripting and project management
- In-depth knowledge of relational databases (PostgreSQL, MySQL) and NoSQL databases (MongoDB)
- Familiarity with various operating systems (Linux, Mac OS, Windows)
- Analytical mind with problem-solving aptitude
- Ability to work independently and within groups.
- Excellent organizational and leadership skills

0 N D U S O

Senior Full-stack Engineer

walterokenye@gmail.com | walterokenye@ymail.com

+254-718-844-831

P.O. Box. 262-00200

Isebania-Kenya

REFEREES

Samuel Mungai

Business Growth and Development Manager,

Equity Bank Limited,

Migori Branch,

Email: samuel.mungai@equitybank.co.ke

Adil Ilyas

CIO,

Smart Banking Solutions Africa,

Email: adil.ilyas@me.com

+1 (631) 538-3172

James Muigai

Manager,

NIC Bank Kenya,

Email: immunene@gmail.com

+254 721 814 192

HOBBIES

Participating in academic forums

Playing Soccer | Playing lawn tennis | Taking part in martial arts